I am an open-minded react native mobile developer who's ready for new challenges. I have spent most of my career in mobile and web development. During the last 10 years, I have developed and published so many iOS and Android application. I am very familiar with not only React native development but also native swift and kotlin app development. On every project, my goal is to reach max efficiency, learn from every experience, and use both to improve the product. In a nutshell, I enjoy challenges, self-improvement, and providing top services.

LinkedIn profile - https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielsong4320220202/

Work History

2022-05 – 2023-05

Senior React Native Mobile Developer

DNA Media Technologies, Inc. Los Angeles, CA

- Senior React Native developer position for developing Revel.xyz social NFT application
- Agile development team.
- Social trading game application development on both of iOS and Android.
- Website link https://www.revel.xyz/, iOS
 application link https://apps.apple.com/app/revel-xyz/id1614465131 and Android application link https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.revel.app

Technologies: iOS, Android, React-Native, Typescript, Firebase, REST api, NFT, Image/Video processing, Twitter and Apple, Instagram 3rd party api connections.

2021-06 -2022-04

Full stack web and mobile developer

ClipIt, LLC, Los Angeles, CA

- 1 year contract (extended more months for maintanence working) to work for web and mobile app for ClipIt social community application
- Worked in a remote team to deliver the product.
- Full stack development service including backend (by using Firebase) and web admin front-end, web

Daniel Song Sr. Mobile Developer

Contact

Address

Silver Spring, Maryland

Phone

(657) 222-0665

E-mail

daniel124eng@gmail.com

Work Authorization

US citizenship

Skills

Software Development

11 years

Programming

11 years

React

8 years

React-Native

6 years

Mobile App Development

9 years

Javascript

9 years

front-end and mobile application (for iOS and Android).

- Video social sharing platform, integrated with other social communities such as Twitter, xbox, Instagram and Facebook.
- Web app link: https://clipit-community.web.app

App store link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/clip-it-community-for-gamers/id1514054242

Technologies: Firebase, iOS, Android, Node.js, Swift, Kotlin, React Web development, React-Native, Video sharing, Social SDKs

2020-05 -2021-05

Senior React Native Mobile Developer

ezCater, Boston, MA

- 1 Year contract working to develop food delivery mobile application development
- Worked in a remote team to deliver the product.
- Developed REST api client, service layer and customized UI components.
- Created unit tests by using Jest
- Available in the app store https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ezcater-businesscatering/id1162865183
- Technologies: React native iOS and Android,
 TypeScript, GraphQL, Apollo Client, food delivery,
 Push notification, Unit Test, CI/CD

2019-04 -2020-04

Senior Mobile Developer

YouSound Inc, San Francisco, CA

- Used React native, developed RN components for player, sound music
- Developed iOS application from scratching by alone, used TypeScript for app development.
- Implemented full audio and video streaming services by using React-Native Type script.
- Created native components to interact with RN
- Available in the app store https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1452078262.
- Technologies: iOS app development, React Native,



5 years

typescript, REST apis, Music player, Streaming - Developed iOS music social application in the company.

2018-01 -2019-03

Principle Software Engineer

Building Engines, Inc., San Francisco, CA

- Worked on the enterprise real estate platform that improves net operating income across the world's most successful Commercial Real Estate portfolios.
- Build core High-level building module within employees and Accounting Module - Write modularized, scalable, robust, and reusable modules and codes to tackle technical debts using best practices.
- Update Accessibility and Built different modules for Work Order, Preventive Maintenance, Invoice Management, Equipment, Admin Accounting, and etc.
- Technologies: React, Redux, Redux Form,
 Python/Django, Jest, Cypress, Storybook, Angular,
 React Native, Node.is

2017-01 -2017-12

Senior Mobile Engineer

TheGrint Inc, San Francisco, CA

- Google Map SDK, React-Native, iOS, Android, REST apis, GPS location programming, Apple Watch Interface
- Developed Google Map view overlay components for the Grint mobile application.
- Implemented REST apis, Table type scoring components for playing.
- Implemented Apple watch interface for the app.
- Worked in a team, communicated in Slack for team, managed tasks in Jira
- Available in the app store https://apps.apple.com/us/app/thegrint-golfhandicap-tracker/id532085262
- Available in the play store https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com
 .grint.thegrint.pro.

REST APIs 7 years Jest 5 years **Unit Test** 8 years Git 9 years Jira 6 years Slack 5 years Xcode 9 years Android Studio 5 years **BLE** 2 years

2015-03 -2016-12

Senior Web and Mobile Developer

ClearAppDevelopment, LLC, San Francisco, CA

- Worked on several web and mobile projects in software agency - ClearAppDevelopment, LLC.
- Worked as a senior software enginer in various of company project such as variaFandando – Mobile application development project, Fitness mobile application and web services development projects.
- Fandandgo app is available in the app store https://apps.apple.com/app/fandango-moviestimes-tickets/id307906541
- Fandando app is available in the google play store https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com .fandango.
- Technologies: iOS App development, Android app development, Mobile, Rest APIs, Redux, SSO, BLE, FitnessKit

2012-01 -

Software Engineer

2014-02

General Assembly, Silver Spring, MD

- Intern and practice for various programming languages

2011-08 -

Software Engineer Intern

2011-12

Starbucks, Silver Spring, MD

- Researching and studying various programming language skills.

Education

2007 - 2011

Bachelor's degree: Computer Science and Mathematics

University of Maryland

Daniel Song

• Silver Spring, MD, US

Contact Information

• 3hs-bxs-sor@mail.dice.com

Summary

I am an open-minded react native mobile developer who's ready for new challenges. I have spent most of my career in mobile and web development. During the last 10 years, I have developed and published so many iOS and Android application. I am very familiar with not only React native development but also native swift and kotlin app development. On every project, my goal is to reach max efficiency, learn from every experience, and use both to improve the product. In a nutshell, I enjoy challenges, self-improvement, and providing top services.

Work History

Total Work Experience: 11 years

- Senior Frontend Developer DNA Media Technologies, Inc May 01, 2022
- Full Stack Mobile Developer Clipit Inc Jun 01, 2021
- Senior Mobile Developer Ezcater
 May 01, 2020
- Senior Mobile Developer Yousound Inc Apr 01, 2019
- Principle Software Engineer Building Engines
 Jan 01, 2018

• Senior Mobile Engineer Thegrint Inc

Jan 01, 2017

 Senior Web And Mobile Developer Clearappdevelopment, LLC Mar 01, 2015

Software Engineer General Assembly

Jan 01, 2012

Education

• Bachelors | University of Maryland

Skills

- xcode 12 years
- android 10 years
- javascript 7 years
- mobile development 7 years
- react 7 years
- react native 7 years
- rest api 7 years
- typescript 7 years
- web development 7 years
- **ios** 6 years
- aws 5 years
- firebase 5 years
- git 5 years
- kotlin 5 years
- swift 5 years
- graphql 4 years
- microsoft azure 4 years
- node.js 4 years
- front-end 3 years

Work Preferences

• Likely to Switch: True

- Willing to Relocate: False
- Travel Preference: 0%
- Work Authorization:
 - o US
- Work Documents:
 - o US Citizen
- Desired Hourly Rate: 73+ (USD)
- Desired Salary: 150,000+ (USD)
- Security Clearance: False
- Third Party: False
- Employment Type:
 - o Full-time
 - o Contract Independent
 - o Contract to Hire Independent
 - o Contract to Hire W2

Profile Sources

- linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielsong4320220202
- Dice: https://www.dice.com/employer/talent/profile/91d2b7233fffbf0df8b909aca59f9bdc